<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Aaron Schraner</title>
    <link>http://aaronschraner.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Aaron Schraner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 22:59:14 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://aaronschraner.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>High Brightness LED Glasses</title>
      <link>http://aaronschraner.com/posts/glasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 22:59:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aaronschraner.com/posts/glasses/</guid>
      <description>Description This project started as a last minute birthday present idea for a friend of mine who is also an electrical engineer.
The idea started in 2018 when I decided to prank him by waking him up with some high brightness LEDs I had recently bought:
The LEDs run at about 18 volts at 3A max so to power them I originally used my benchtop power supply
The goal with this project was to do something similar but make it portable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Safety Circuit</title>
      <link>http://aaronschraner.com/posts/safety-circuit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 19:40:29 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aaronschraner.com/posts/safety-circuit/</guid>
      <description>Description This circuit was a part of my senior design project, an electronic throttle for the OSU formula racing team. As part of the very long list of safety requirements an electronic throttle has to meet in order to participate in formula racing, there has to be a non-programmable safety circuit that is capable of cutting power to the engine if the throttle is open by more than 10% and the driver is braking hard for more than one second.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimeter Watch</title>
      <link>http://aaronschraner.com/posts/multimeter-watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 17:48:56 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aaronschraner.com/posts/multimeter-watch/</guid>
      <description>Description This project is a small form-factor digital multimeter capable of measuring DC voltage (up to +/-60V) and resistance. It is powered by an ADS1115 ADC module and ATMega328P microcontroller. The screen is a Broadcom HCMS-2912 dot matrix display, which has integrated brightness control and refresh circuitry. I built it in Spring 2017.
Features The multimeter is capable of measuring DC voltage up to +/- 60 Volts and resistance from 100 ohms to 50 kohms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LED Strip Audio Visualizer</title>
      <link>http://aaronschraner.com/posts/led-strip-audio-vis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 18:38:28 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aaronschraner.com/posts/led-strip-audio-vis/</guid>
      <description>Description This project uses an Arduino MEGA 2560 to continuously perform an FFT on an audio signal and display it on an LED strip. It can also adjust the volume of my speakers with a remote control. The remote works reliably up to about 40 feet away (through 1-2 walls).
Visualizer The visualizer part of the code uses Tom Roberts&amp;rsquo; fixed-point FFT library and displays the result on an Adafruit DotStar LED strip.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Breadboard Nixie Tube Clock</title>
      <link>http://aaronschraner.com/posts/breadboard-nixie-tube-clock/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 16:54:07 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aaronschraner.com/posts/breadboard-nixie-tube-clock/</guid>
      <description>Description This project is a digital clock that uses IN-14 nixie tubes to display the time. It is controlled by a raspberry pi using shift registers. I did this project in 2016 but didn&amp;rsquo;t have any online documentation except for the github repo and a youtube video until now. One of the key features of this project is that since it is powered by a raspberry pi, it can be easily controlled from within python or bash scripts, and is automatically network synchronized as long as the pi has an internet connection.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>